<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Miguel Aspis&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Miguel Aspis&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Image Captioning</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/image-captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/image-captioning/</guid>
      <description>Image Captioning project done using Keras and Tensorflow and trained o the flickr8kdataset applying visual attention using EfficientNetB0 to extract image embeddings and then training a transformer model based on the original architecture to provide captions. More can be read in the notebook located on the project&amp;rsquo;s github repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunspot Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/sunspot-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/sunspot-forecast/</guid>
      <description>Time series forecasting project done on the monthly mean sunspot number 1749-2018 dataset using Tensroflow and Keras Sequential API to design a number of very simple models to test on this problem, the goal was not to get the performance possible but to recall the workflow of working with time series data and how to do forecasting with it. More can be read in the notebook located on the project&amp;rsquo;s github repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Classification</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/music-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/music-classification/</guid>
      <description>Music classification project with the intent of classifying different songs based on their genre using the Marsyas dataset and using 2 architectures, a small convolutional neural network and a recurrent neural network with LSTM cells. Accompanied by audio preprocessing routine which was done on each music sample to be able to feed it to the NNs using the librosa library. The whole project can be seen on the github repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Chatbot</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Simple chatbot developed in Python trained using nltk for Natural language processing and Tensorflow for training the model, using a simple feedforward neural network. The GUI was programmed using tkinter. More can be seen in the project&amp;rsquo;s github repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Recommender System</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/film-recommender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/film-recommender/</guid>
      <description>Notebook with exploratory data analysis, seeing relationships and interesting facts in the data, with some visualizations and development of 2 basic recommender systems, one based on correlation between movies and the other using the K Nearest Neighbor algorithm. More can be read on the notebook available at the github repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/image-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/image-classification/</guid>
      <description>Basic Image classification A project done using a simple CNN architecture to do image classification on the CIFAR-10 dataset.
Steps of the process include:
 Importing the data One-hot enconding it Defining 1st basic CNN using Keras high-level Sequential API Training and evaluating Defining a bit bigger model Training and evaluating Comparing both and concluding  more can be read on the project&amp;rsquo;s github repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber data visualization</title>
      <link>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/uber-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelaspis.github.io/Miguel_Portfolio/blog/uber-viz/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization project on dataset with uber trips data on New York city in the year 2014. Some interesting information could be gathered regarding costumer&amp;rsquo;s habits and patterns. One of such visualizations can be seen here:
More of these can be seen on the github repo</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
